<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (5.2.8#851-sha1:3262fdc28b4bc8b23784e13eadc26a22399f5d88) at Tue Jul 16 13:21:57 UTC 2013

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary add field=key&field=summary to the URL of your request.
For example:
https://issues.apache.org/jira/si/jira.issueviews:issue-xml/LUCENE-2323/LUCENE-2323.xml?field=key&field=summary
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>5.2.8</version>
        <build-number>851</build-number>
        <build-date>26-02-2013</build-date>
    </build-info>

<item>
            <title>[LUCENE-2323] reorganize contrib modules</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-2323</link>
                <project id="12310110" key="LUCENE">Lucene - Core</project>
                        <description>&lt;p&gt;it would be nice to reorganize contrib modules, so that they are bundled together by functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the wikipedia contrib is a tokenizer, i think really belongs in contrib/analyzers&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;there are two highlighters, i think could be one highlighters package.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;there are many queryparsers and queries in different places in contrib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <environment></environment>
            <key id="12459082">LUCENE-2323</key>
            <summary>reorganize contrib modules</summary>
                <type id="4" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/issuetypes/improvement.png">Improvement</type>
                                <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.png">Major</priority>
                    <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png">Closed</status>
                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                <assignee username="rcmuir">Robert Muir</assignee>
                                <reporter username="rcmuir">Robert Muir</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 18:10:21 +0000</created>
                <updated>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:27 +0100</updated>
                    <resolved>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 01:45:05 +0100</resolved>
                                            <fixVersion>3.1</fixVersion>
                <fixVersion>4.0-ALPHA</fixVersion>
                                <component>modules/other</component>
                        <due></due>
                    <votes>0</votes>
                        <watches>0</watches>
                                                    <comments>
                    <comment id="12845115" author="shaie" created="Sun, 14 Mar 2010 18:21:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That&apos;d be great !&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12845128" author="mikemccand" created="Sun, 14 Mar 2010 20:30:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1!!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846522" author="rcmuir" created="Wed, 17 Mar 2010 18:44:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Here are my initial thoughts on this. &lt;br/&gt;
I don&apos;t think we have to do the entire thing at one time either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;fold contrib/regex into contrib/queries:
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;alongside &apos;similar&apos; you would see &apos;regex&apos;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;fold the four queryparsers in contrib/misc into contrib/queryparser, so under o.a.l.qp you would see:
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;core&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;standard&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;complexPhrase&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;ext&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;precedence&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;analyzing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;fold the fast-vector-highlighter under highlighter, so under o.a.l.search you would see:
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;highlight&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;vectorhighlight&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In a second phase, potentially a different issue, i would like to discuss issues that might involve backwards breaks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;xml-query-parser: really belongs in contrib/queryparser, but we would have to change pkg names.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;wikipedia: really belongs in analysis, but we would have to change pkg names.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;contrib/surround: what to do? has both queryparser and queries, maybe should stay as is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Any objections to doing the first part, which has no pkg naming changes?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846543" author="mikemccand" created="Wed, 17 Mar 2010 19:27:53 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are my initial thoughts on this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1, I think this initial re-org is great Robert!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&apos;d be OK to rename XML QP and Wikipedia as well.  Surround does seem trickier... maybe leave that for now.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846602" author="shaie" created="Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:26:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Robert - I think that&apos;s great reorganization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do want to propose to omit the component name from the package (where it makes sense). I.e., unless we want to have o.a.l.qp, it doesn&apos;t mean that all QPs under contrib/queryParser need to belong to the same package. If it makes sense for all of them to belong to o.a.l.search (as an example), then that&apos;s where they should go, IMO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think it&apos;s ok if under contrib/queryparser or contrib/analyzers you&apos;ll see packages like o.a.l.analysis.ar/fr/snowball, as well as I&apos;m perfectly fine if all of them exist under o.a.l.analysis. Analysis makes sense as a package name.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846606" author="kaykay.unique" created="Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:47:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;When we talk about reorganization - it would be useful to run by some jdepend reports at -  &lt;a href=&quot;http://clarkware.com/software/JDepend.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;http://clarkware.com/software/JDepend.html&lt;/a&gt; , as a metric for the stability of the packages. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846620" author="rcmuir" created="Wed, 17 Mar 2010 22:23:12 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do want to propose to omit the component name from the package (where it makes sense).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shai, I agree its a little redundant, yet under this issue I wanted to avoid changing package names &lt;br/&gt;
as much as possible: changing the package name breaks people&apos;s code and thats why I wanted&lt;br/&gt;
to just do the first part, with no pkg naming changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought these initial svn moves are obvious wins, and any further stuff can be done later under another&lt;br/&gt;
issue... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically I would prefer to do a full reorganization at once, but in my opinion that is for a later, probably&lt;br/&gt;
longer and more frustrating discussion, and it needs to involve Solr, too.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846700" author="hossman" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:49:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I personally don&apos;t have a strong opinion on this, but i wanted to point it out for completeness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the last time i remember a big discussion about reorging contribs, there seemed to be a strong sentiment that we should be striving for more &quot;small&quot; contribs/modules &amp;#8211; specificly in terms of artifact size/complexity.  I think one specific example was that some poeple might want a few langauge specific analyzers, but not all of them &amp;#8211; and if they have no direct dependencies on each other (just core) we should try to build/distribute them as (tiny) individual Jars &amp;#8211; and possible in (big) bundled jars as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while it might make a lot of sense to organize some existing contribs into logical &quot;groups&quot; which might get build up in big bundled jars, there are likely going to be people who still want to comsume the existing jars (or even more granular jars)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the specific suggestions robert made: it makes sense to logically organize all the query parsers under a common directory, but how many users are actually using more then one and are we doing them a disservice if we only ship them in one big jar?   Ditto for the highlighters (does anyone besides Solr use &lt;b&gt;both&lt;/b&gt; highlighters in a single application?)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846702" author="rcmuir" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:59:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hoss Man, the only problem I have with what you said, is that it prevents factoring the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I want to refactor some code among our 7 queryparsers or 2 highlighters or whatever, &lt;br/&gt;
the only way I can do this is to shove stuff (shared code) into core, I think this is bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I don&apos;t really care how things are packaged, this proposal was supposed to be&lt;br/&gt;
a small step towards modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                    <comment id="12846707" author="hossman" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 01:10:06 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I want to refactor some code among our 7 queryparsers or 2 highlighters or whatever, the only way I can do this is to shove stuff (shared code) into core, I think this is bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;agreed ... IIRC the idea in this discussion was the have a lot more smaller &quot;modules&quot;, with a lot better defined/advertised dependencies, so that module X,Y,Z might all depend on modules A, and B (which had the common refactored code you speak of) and the &quot;core&quot; module is special in that it must never depend on anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like i said: I personally don&apos;t have a very strong opinion about this, i think people who are really concerned about jar sizes can compile their own after pruning the classes they don&apos;t care about &amp;#8211; but it&apos;s definitely harder when those classes are all in one atomic source tree where you might not notice that someone refactored a common dependency that wasn&apos;t there before.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846709" author="rcmuir" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 01:17:35 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;agreed ... IIRC the idea in this discussion was the have a lot more smaller &quot;modules&quot;, with a lot better defined/advertised dependencies, so that module X,Y,Z might all depend on modules A, and B (which had the common refactored code you speak of)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&apos;t know this was the goal, if what you say is true, then I must say i completely&lt;br/&gt;
misunderstood, I completely disagree, and I&apos;m completely off-base with this issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846711" author="markrmiller@gmail.com" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 01:27:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This reorg is a great a great step for contrib IMO!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846712" author="hossman" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 01:43:11 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&apos;t know this was the goal, if what you say is true, then I must say i completely misunderstood, I completely disagree, and I&apos;m completely off-base with this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not saying it is a goal, or should be a goal, just that i seem to remember that this was teh direction that seemed to have support the last time i remember there being a big &quot;reorg the contribs&quot; discussion.  (i could be remembering wrong, it could be that &lt;b&gt;I&lt;/b&gt; thought it was a really great idea at the time so it stuck with me, and now i&apos;m just more ambivalent)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick skim suggests this is the most recent thread i&apos;m thinking of...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://old.nabble.com/New-flexible-query-parser-to22549684.html#a22637326&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;http://old.nabble.com/New-flexible-query-parser-to22549684.html#a22637326&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
(&quot;kitchen sink&quot; was the search term i was looking for)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...but i don&apos;t think that was the first time it came up.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846719" author="rcmuir" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 02:15:06 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;it could be that I thought it was a really great idea at the time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my problem is not in the idea, but that its just unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;more realistic, lets say for the queryparsers would be, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;moving the queryparsers together as i proposed here&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;implementing some of the specialized ones with the new flexible queryparser (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-1823&quot; title=&quot;QueryParser with new features for Lucene 3&quot;&gt;LUCENE-1823&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;removing the now obselete specialized queryparsers.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;improving tests and general quality of the queryparsing package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At this point the code might be mature enough for an idea like yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m also realistic, and I know I probably cannot do much here except step 1, as I&apos;m not a queryparser expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can say there&apos;s at least a patch open for step 2, even if this patch might not yet be ready.&lt;br/&gt;
So this seems like a realistic small step forward towards improving things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modularization idea won&apos;t cleanup contrib... some of it is hairy and that needs to be done first.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846744" author="shaie" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:08:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Robert - I think that&apos;s exactly what I was proposing. You indicated that there are some components under contrib that you cannot move around because their package names would change, and I said that I don&apos;t think their package names should change &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.gif&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;. So you can move XMLQP under contrib/queryparsers and its package name will stay the same ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think that at least for analyzers, having all of them under one contrib jar will allow us to improve the way our users interact w/ analyzers. Consider for example an AnalyzerFactory which when receiving a Locale returns a pre-configured Analyzer, the best one we can think of for that Locale. That&apos;s (to me) a great service to our users, and I don&apos;t see how we can do that if all analyzers are under different modules. Besides, analyzers are logically close to each other because they perform a very specific task. Refactoring the analysis API again would be easier of all of them were under the same root directory ... less chance of missing some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Query parsers are different because I agree a user will likely pick one for his app and go with it. But I don&apos;t think we&apos;re talking about massive amount of code here right? So again it makes sense to bundle them up together. We can have a module-level documentation of the different query parsers, pros and cons for each, use cases etc., and then the user can pick. If jar size is important to someone, then I think that someone is already recompiling everything to include just what he needs, and so we&apos;re not hurting anyone here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore I see this reorg as a logical and important step towards modularization.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846752" author="rcmuir" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:33:37 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I don&apos;t think we&apos;re talking about massive amount of code here right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hopefully less code if we can put some of these things together and&lt;br/&gt;
start looking at refactoring them a bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until code in contrib is to a certain degree of maturity, I feel we should organize&lt;br/&gt;
it by functionality. Its easy for the users, and it invites the sort of refactoring and &lt;br/&gt;
cleanup that some of this code needs.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12846798" author="mikemccand" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 09:07:43 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until code in contrib is to a certain degree of maturity, I feel we should organize&lt;br/&gt;
it by functionality. Its easy for the users, and it invites the sort of refactoring and&lt;br/&gt;
cleanup that some of this code needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                    <comment id="12847213" author="rcmuir" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 03:00:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;attached is a patch for the first moves outlined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before applying the patch, please run the following script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;# regex -&amp;gt; queries
svn move lucene/contrib/regex/lib lucene/contrib/queries
svn move lucene/contrib/regex/src/java/org/apache/lucene/search/regex lucene/contrib/queries/src/java/org/apache/lucene/search
svn move lucene/contrib/regex/src/java/org/apache/regexp lucene/contrib/queries/src/java/org/apache
svn move lucene/contrib/regex/src/test/org/apache/lucene/search/regex lucene/contrib/queries/src/test/org/apache/lucene/search
svn delete lucene/contrib/regex

# fast-vector-highlighter -&amp;gt; highlighter
svn move lucene/contrib/fast-vector-highlighter/src/java/org/apache/lucene/search/vectorhighlight lucene/contrib/highlighter/src/java/org/apache/lucene/search
svn move lucene/contrib/fast-vector-highlighter/src/test/org/apache/lucene/search/vectorhighlight lucene/contrib/highlighter/src/test/org/apache/lucene/search
svn delete lucene/contrib/fast-vector-highlighter

# misc/queryparsers -&amp;gt; queryparser
svn move lucene/contrib/misc/src/java/org/apache/lucene/queryParser/* lucene/contrib/queryparser/src/java/org/apache/lucene/queryParser
svn move lucene/contrib/misc/src/test/org/apache/lucene/queryParser/* lucene/contrib/queryparser/src/test/org/apache/lucene/queryParser
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no one objects, (especially including Hoss Man), I would like to commit in &lt;br/&gt;
a day or two, but keeping the issue open, and doing the more complex ones&lt;br/&gt;
next.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12847269" author="paul.elschot@xs4all.nl" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 08:22:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Would it be possible to move surround to the query parsers, too?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12847313" author="rcmuir" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 11:17:44 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would it be possible to move surround to the query parsers, too? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I think we want to do this. I can do it in the second patch with the other moves.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12848853" author="hossman" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2010 18:59:11 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If no one objects, (especially including Hoss Man)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really have no opinions, I was just trying to chime in with my memories of hte past discussions &amp;#8211; i don&apos;t necessarily think one way or another is more good/bad right/wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;go with your gut.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12850012" author="rcmuir" created="Fri, 26 Mar 2010 05:25:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed 927696 (and 927697 for the solr piece).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will keep the issue open and work on a patch for the next part.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12855503" author="rcmuir" created="Fri, 9 Apr 2010 19:08:31 +0100"  >&lt;p&gt;now that flex is merged, its a good time to continue doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attached is a patch to move WikipediaTokenizer to contrib/analyzers and remove contrib/wikipedia (there is nothing else in it).&lt;br/&gt;
it also adds the factory and test to Solr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before applying the patch, you must run the following svn commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;
mkdir lucene/contrib/analyzers/common/src/java/org/apache/lucene/analysis/wikipedia
svn add lucene/contrib/analyzers/common/src/java/org/apache/lucene/analysis/wikipedia
mkdir lucene/contrib/analyzers/common/src/test/org/apache/lucene/analysis/wikipedia
svn add lucene/contrib/analyzers/common/src/test/org/apache/lucene/analysis/wikipedia
svn move lucene/contrib/wikipedia/src/java/org/apache/lucene/wikipedia/analysis/* lucene/contrib/analyzers/common/src/java/org/apache/lucene/analysis/wikipedia
svn move lucene/contrib/wikipedia/src/test/org/apache/lucene/wikipedia/analysis/* lucene/contrib/analyzers/common/src/test/org/apache/lucene/analysis/wikipedia
svn rm lucene/contrib/wikipedia
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if no one objects, I would like to commit this soon.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12855565" author="rcmuir" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2010 14:51:23 +0100"  >&lt;p&gt;attached is a patch to move surround to contrib/queryparser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before applying the patch please run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;svn move lucene/contrib/surround/src/java/org/apache/lucene/queryParser/surround lucene/contrib/queryparser/src/java/org/apache/lucene/queryParser/
svn move lucene/contrib/surround/src/test/org/apache/lucene/queryParser/surround lucene/contrib/queryparser/src/test/org/apache/lucene/queryParser/
svn move lucene/contrib/surround/README.txt lucene/contrib/queryparser
svn delete lucene/contrib/surround
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="12864721" author="rcmuir" created="Thu, 6 May 2010 11:44:34 +0100"  >&lt;p&gt;i backported changes thus far to stable: 941649&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    <comment id="13013487" author="gsingers" created="Wed, 30 Mar 2011 16:50:27 +0100"  >&lt;p&gt;Bulk close for 3.1&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    <attachment id="12441341" name="ASF.LICENSE.NOT.GRANTED--LUCENE-2323_surround.patch" size="50242" author="rcmuir" created="Sat, 10 Apr 2010 14:51:23 +0100" />
                    <attachment id="12439234" name="LUCENE-2323.patch" size="20092" author="rcmuir" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 03:00:47 +0000" />
                    <attachment id="12441323" name="LUCENE-2323_wikipedia.patch" size="46745" author="rcmuir" created="Fri, 9 Apr 2010 19:08:28 +0100" />
                </attachments>
            <subtasks>
        </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                <customfieldvalues>
                    <customfieldvalue>3.0</customfieldvalue>
                </customfieldvalues>
            </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310220" key="com.atlassian.jira.ext.charting:firstresponsedate">
                <customfieldname>Date of First Response</customfieldname>
                <customfieldvalues>
                    <customfieldvalue>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 18:21:57 +0000</customfieldvalue>

                </customfieldvalues>
            </customfield>
                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                <customfieldvalues>
                    <customfieldvalue>11471</customfieldvalue>
                </customfieldvalues>
            </customfield>
                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310120" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multicheckboxes">
                <customfieldname>Lucene Fields</customfieldname>
                <customfieldvalues>
                        <customfieldvalue key="10121"><![CDATA[New]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                </customfieldvalues>
            </customfield>
                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                <customfieldvalues>
                    <customfieldvalue>25402</customfieldvalue>
                </customfieldvalues>
            </customfield>
                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310222" key="com.atlassian.jira.ext.charting:timeinstatus">
                <customfieldname>Time in Status</customfieldname>
                <customfieldvalues>
                    
                </customfieldvalues>
            </customfield>
                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>